Sakaguchi Ango
坂口安吾
Sakaguchi Ango.
A Mysterious Intellectual...
A mysterious intellectual...
インテリでミステリアスな男
そして
And...
誰も君の正体を知らない
No One Knew Who You Really Were
No one knew who you really were.
Western-style Food
and Curry
Freedom
カレーの味はどうだい？
How's the curry taste?
The same as usual.
いつも通りだ
子ども達の様子はどうだ
How are the kids doing?
The same as usual.
いつも通りだよ
みんな二階にいるから　顔出してやって
They're all upstairs,
so why don't you go say hi?
It's me. I'm coming in.
俺だ　入るぞ
元気か
How are you guys doing?
You're not causing the old man
any trouble, are you?
親爺さんに迷惑かけてないか
I've got you now!
も～らったぁ
Hup!
こら
食らえ
こらこらこらこら
どうだ　織田作　参ったか
How's that, Odasaku? You give up?
Apparently I'm going to have to show you
just how scary the real mafia is...
本物のマフィアの恐ろしさを教えてやる必要があるな
参ったか
You give up?
Nope!
参らない
Then...
ならば…
Let's have some Port Mafia-style torture.
ポートマフィア流の拷問といこう
やめろ　死ぬ　死ぬ
Stop! I'll die! I'll die!
やめろ　ほんとっ　やめて　嫌だ
No! Stop! Seriously, stop! Stop!
I'll definitely get you next time.
次は必ず仕留める
I'll look forward to it.
楽しみにしている
辛っ
Hot! This is too hot.
辛いよ　おじさん　これ隠し味に溶岩でも入ってるの
Did you add lava as the secret
ingredient or something?
Odasaku-chan eats that all the time.
織田作ちゃんはいつもそれ食べてるよ
How were the kids?
ああ　子ども達はどうだった？
いつも通りだ
The same as usual.
Are those all the kids
that lost their parents in
二年前の龍頭抗争で親を亡くした子ども達かい
the Ryuuzu Dispute two years ago?
決して殺さず
You're Oda Sakunosuke.
出世に興味がなく
A member of the mafia who never kills,
孤児を養うマフィア
you have no interest in moving up,
織田作之助
and you take care of orphans.
You sure are strange.
変わってるねぇ
You're the strangest person
in the Port Mafia.
ポートマフィアの中で一番変わってるよ
Not as strange as you.
お前ほどじゃない
Here are the living expenses for
those kids for the time being.
親爺さん　子ども達の当面の生活費だ
Are you sure? I don't mind pitching in...
大丈夫なのかい　よければうちでもいくらか負担を
I'm already grateful that you're
giving them a place to stay.
親爺さんには場所を貸してもらって感謝してる
それに俺はこの店のカレーがいつでも食えるだけで十分だ
And as long as I get to eat the
curry here whenever I want,
Hot... So hot...
辛ぇ　辛ぇ…
I don't need anything else.
And you came here today
concerning that thing, right?
今日来たのは例の件だな
Yes...
そ…そうですー
結論から云うと　彼らは海外の異能犯罪組織だった
I've come to the conclusion
that they are an organization
of gifted members from overseas.
They were being chased by a
gifted agency from England
英国の異能機関「時計塔の従騎士」に追われ
called the Order of the Clock Tower,
欧州からほうほうの体で逃げてきたらしい
and came scurrying from Europe to Japan...
そんな奴らがわざわざ日本まで来て　何をしようとしてる
And what did those guys come
all the way to Japan for?
They escaped to a foreign land...
逃げた先は異国の地　先立つ者がいるってことかな
So maybe something was already here...
That's possible... But there's one
thing that bugs me about that.
ありそうな話だが　一つ引っかかることがある
You want to say that the soldiers
were far too skilled, right?
兵の練度が高すぎるっていうんだろう
Yeah.
ああ
彼らは軍人崩れだよ
They're former soldiers...
According to my information,
情報に拠ると
組織の頭目は強力な異能力で歴戦の部下達を統率しているらしい
the head of that organization
uses a powerful gift
to command veteran soldiers.
強力な異能力？
Powerful gift?
Does the boss know about this?
首領はこの件のことを知ってるのか
報告したよ
I reported it to him.
そうしたら　対ミミックの戦略立案と前線指揮を仰せつかった
Then he ordered me to come up with an
anti-Mimic strategy and command the front.
早速いくつか罠を仕掛けておいた
I already set up various traps.
根本的なことを聞くが
I'm going to ask you something
rather rudimentary,
国際的な異能力犯罪組織ならば　政府機関の案件ではないのか
but if it's an international criminal
organization with gifted members,
wouldn't this be a matter for the government agency?
それは内務省異能特務課のことを云っているのかな
Are you referring to the Ministry of Home Affairs'
Supernatural Special Operations Division?
They won't show up unless the
situation is rather extreme.
彼らは滅多なことでは出張ってこない
表向きは存在しない組織だからね
Because to the outside world,
they technically don't even exist.
安吾については
And what about Ango?
It's basically been confirmed that Ango
武器庫の暗証番号は安吾に拠ってもたらされたものだとほぼ確定した
was the one who leaked the
passcode on the storage unit.
Did Ango betray the organization?
安吾は組織を裏切ったのか
そう考えると　凡ての辻褄は合う
Everything makes perfect
sense if we believe that.
私だよ
It's me.
了解した
Understood.
ネズミが罠にかかった
A mouse fell into one of my traps.
Episode 14: Nowhere to Return
Just like our information said.
情報通りだ
Unlocked
What?
なに
催眠瓦斯…　罠か
Sleeping gas... So this was a trap.
This is an accounting facility that the
Port Mafia uses for money laundering.
ここはポートマフィアが資金洗浄する為の会計施設だ
三年前　ポートマフィアにスカウトされた坂口安吾は暫くここで働いていた
Three years ago, Sakaguchi Ango
was scouted by the Port Mafia,
and worked here for a while.
ここには安吾の記録がある
There are records of Ango here.
Well, I'm going to get to work.
それじゃ　わしは仕事をしとりますからのう
Please don't mind me.
お構いなく
いい職場だ
This is a great place to work.
Maybe I'll ask to be transferred here.
ここに配置換えを願おうかな
そう云ってくる若者は大抵三日ともたずに飛び出していきますのじゃ
Every youngster that's ever said that
usually goes running out of
here in less than three days.
退屈すぎてのう
Because it's too boring.
ごゆっくり
Please, take your time.
I found some information that bothered me.
一つ気になる記述を発見した
Two years ago, Ango went to
Europe on a business trip.
二年前　安吾は欧州に出張に行っている
The purpose was to negotiate a deal
with a local stolen car broker.
目的は現地の盗難車ブローカーと商談を結ぶ為だが
この時か　彼らと二重間諜の契約を結んだのは
That must be when
he agreed to become a
double agent for them.
This was the place where
Dazai and I first met Ango.
ここは俺と太宰が初めて安吾に会った場所だ
それ以上近寄らないでもらえます
Would you mind not coming any closer?
You smell.
臭うので
二年前　龍頭抗争の只中
Two years ago, during the Ryuuzu Dispute,
Dazai and I got orders from above
俺と太宰は上からの命令で
and were put in charge of taking
care of the corpses
抗争で死んだ構成員の死体を片付ける役を仰せつかっていた
臭いの
of organization members
who had died in the dispute.
Do I smell...?
Mostly, it was to bring
back their belongings.
主に所持品を持ち帰る仕事だ
それらが警察に入手されると　組織犯罪防止法の証拠品とされて
If the police were to get
their hands on them,
they could be used as evidence for
the organized crime prevention law
厄介なことになる
and it would be rather troublesome.
君は新入りだね
You must be new.
State your name.
名前を云いたまえ
It's Sakaguchi Ango.
坂口安吾ですが
安吾君　君は実に面白いね
Ango-kun...
You are truly amusing.
You reek!
臭っ
こんなことをしても　首領は嫌がるばかりだと思うよ
I'm pretty sure the boss isn't going
to like you doing things like this.
Are you trying to say that
you know what I'm doing?
僕が何をしてるかわかるとでも云うのですか
君は死者の人生録を作ってる　違うかい
You're making a life record
of those who died.
Am I wrong?
A life record of those who died?
死者の人生録
昨夜発生した幹部襲撃事件でのこちらの死者は三名
These three died in the incident
that happened last night where
executives were attacked.
Umeki Kurehito, Saegusa Shoukichi,
Ishige Miroku.
梅木紅人　三枝昭吉　石毛巳六
梅木は元軍警で　同僚殺しの汚名を着せられ除名　両親とも死別
Umeki was a former MP.
He was dishonorably discharged
for killing a coworker.
Both of his parents had died.
You're recording the dead's history
and family information, as well.
死者の経歴や家族構成まで記録に残している
The death of a person is
not just some number.
人の死は数字じゃない
Every one of their lives
must have some meaning.
一人一人の生には必ず意味がある
What's written here is something
you could never feel
ここに書き付けてあるのは「三人死亡」という一言からは決して感じることのできない
from just the words, "three dead."
彼らの息遣いです
It's their breath.
What did the boss say about this?
この件で首領はなんと
今まで抗争で亡くなった８４人分凡て僕が無理矢理押し付けました
I forced all 84 people who have died
so far in the dispute upon him.
At first, he hated it,
最初は嫌がっていましたが
今では組織全体の実情を知る貴重な情報源だと喜んでいますけど
but now he says it's valuable information
to get to know everything
about the organization
and was rather pleased.
ねぇ　面白いでしょう
See? Isn't he amusing?
どんなきっかけあればこんなユニークな仕事を思いつくのかね
What kind of circumstances cause one to
think up such a unique job as this?
There's one way to find out...
知る方法が一つある
We just need to take him to
our usual place after this.
この後　いつもの店に彼も連れていけばいい
そりゃあ妙案だ
That's a brilliant idea.
I'm not going!
行きませんよ　僕は他にも仕事が…
織田作　彼を忙しさから解放する方法が一つある
I have other work I need to do!
Odasaku! There's one way to free him up!
我々が彼に思いきり抱きつけば
If we hug him as hard as we can,
臭いと汚泥とで今日はもう仕事にならない
he won't be able to work anymore
from the smell and the filth!
Okay.
わかった
Hold it!
ちょっと待った
こ…これは一張羅で　やめなさいこんなこと
This is my best suit! Stop this!
怒りますよ　本当に怒りますよ
I'm going to get angry!
I'm seriously going to get angry!
I'd like an explanation...
説明が欲しいな
We captured Mimic's vanguard
that attacked the casino
カジノを襲撃したミミックの尖兵を計画通り　昏倒性の瓦斯で捕らえました
with the knockout gas as planned.
One of them committed suicide,
but we brought the other three here.
一人は自殺しましたが　残りの三人はここに運びました
仲間の情報を吐かせる手筈でした
We were planning to have them
talk about the others.
We even removed the poison
hidden in their teeth.
奥歯に仕込んだ自決用の毒薬も取り外しました
I know that.
それは知ってるよ
Because this was all part of my plan.
凡て私の計画通りだからね
聞きたいのはその先だ
What I want to know is what
happened after that...
O-One of the soldiers woke up
earlier than expected.
そ…想像よりも早く兵士の一人が目覚めました
Before we could get handcuffs on him,
手枷を嵌める前に我々から銃を奪い
he stole one of our guns
and most likely shot his comrades
so they couldn't talk.
恐らくは口封じの為に仲間を射殺し
我々にも襲いかかってきました
He also came after us...
So I decided to take care of it.
それを僕が処断した
Is there a problem?
何か問題でも
I see...
なるほどね
No, it's nothing.
いや　何もないよ
You defeated the fearsome, unyielding enemy,
不撓不屈の恐るべき敵兵士を倒し　仲間を守ったわけだね　芥川君
and protected our comrades, Akutagawa-kun.
That's absolutely splendid.
全くもって素晴らしい
If it weren't for your powers,
君の異能でなければ
そのような強力な敵を一撃の下に倒すことなどできなかったろう
they wouldn't have been able to defeat
such a powerful enemy on
their own in a single blow.
流石は私の部下だ
Nothing less from my subordinate.
Thanks to you, all of the
enemies we captured are dead.
おかげで捕らえた敵は全員　死亡だ
The soldiers that I worked so hard to
lay a trap for just to keep alive...
罠を張ってまで苦労して生け捕りにした兵士をね
これで手がかりはなくなった
Now our clues are gone.
If even one of them were alive, we could
have found out their headquarters, motive,
一人でも生き残っていれば
本拠地　目的　指揮官の素性　名前
their commander's lineage, name,
そして組織を統率する異能力
and the powers they use
to command the organization...
We could have gotten all of
that important information.
貴重な情報を引き出せたろうに
Information?
情報などと　連中如き僕がまとめ…
As if I would—
きっと君は私が云い訳を求めているように見えたのだろう
To you, it must have seemed like I was
waiting to hear some excuse.
誤解させて悪かったね
I'm sorry for giving you the wrong idea.
Hand me your gun.
銃貸して
Someone I know happens to be
taking care of some orphans...
私の知り合いに　孤児を個人的に扶養している男がいてね
If Odasaku happened to pick
you up from the slums,
貧民街で君を拾ったのが織田作だったら
I'm sure that he wouldn't
have abandoned you.
きっと君を見捨てず　辛抱強く導いたろう
He would have patiently
and firmly guided you.
That's what righteousness is...
それが正しさだ
けど私は　その正しさのほうから嫌われた男だ
However, I'm a man hated by righteousness.
Men like me...
そういう男はねぇ
Do this to their useless subordinates.
使えない部下をこうするんだ
Oh?
See? You can do it.
やればできるじゃないか
How many times have I told you?
何度も教えただろう
Cutting open unfortunate hostages
isn't the only thing you're good for.
哀れな捕虜を切り裂くだけが君の力の凡てじゃない
You should be able to use your
powers for defense, too.
そうやって防衛に使うこともできる筈だって
これまで一度も成功させたことはなかったのに
I've never been able to successfully
do that before this.
でもこうして成功した
But you just did.
Isn't that great?
目出度いねぇ
The next time you mess up...
次しくじったら
二回殴って五発撃つ
I'll punch you twice,
and shoot you five times.
Got it?
いいな
Now, then...
却説と
Let's check their corpses.
Something might turn up.
死体を調べてみよう　何か出るかもしれない
Um... What should we check on the corpses?
あの　死体の何をお調べしましょう
Everything.
全部だよ
We're going to find any trace
of their hideout that we can.
アジトの痕跡を見つけ出すんだ
The soles of their shoes, their pocket lint,
靴底　ポケットの屑　服の付着物
anything sticking to their clothes...
凡てが手がかりだ
All of those are clues.
For crying out loud...
まったく
Apparently all of my subordinates
must think that beating our enemy
うちの部下は揃って敵を嬲り殺すだけがマフィアだと思ってる
to death is the only thing the mafia does.
At this rate, Odasaku might figure
this all out on his own.
この調子だと　織田作一人で解決してしまいそうだ
I know that man, as well.
その男なら　私も知っています
Though he is part of the mafia,
he lacks the guts to kill a person.
マフィアの中にあって　人を殺す度胸のない男
I can't see him associating
with you at all, Dazai-san.
とても太宰さんと釣り合う男には見えません
You've made two mistakes.
君の間違いは二つ
釣り合う　釣り合わないに度胸は関係ない
Guts have nothing to do with being able
to associate with someone or not.
The other is a warning.
もう一つは忠告だ
You'd be better off not angering Odasaku...
織田作は怒らせないほうがいいよ　絶対にね
Ever.
If he were to truly become angry
from the bottom of his heart,
もし彼が心の底から怒ったなら　この部屋にいる全員が…
everyone in this room
would be dead before any of
us could draw our guns.
銃を抜く間もなく殺されるよ
When Odasaku isn't holding back,
本気の織田作は　どんなポートマフィアより恐ろしい
he's more terrifying than
any Port Mafia member.
Akutagawa-kun, you could never defeat
Odasaku in a hundred years.
芥川君　君なんか百年経っても織田作には勝てないよ
莫迦な　あり得ない
No... That's impossible...
Dazai-san, who do you think—
太宰さん　あなたは僕を…
All right, back to work.
さあ　仕事に戻るよ
I know the enemy's trouble, but we need
to hurry up and take care of this.
敵も面倒だけど　早く抗争を片付けないと
Or the Supernatural Special Operations Division
will show up and cause even more trouble.
異能特務課が出張ってきて　更に厄介なことになる
This is Oda.
織田です
やあ織田作　手がかりを掴んだ
Hey, Odasaku. I found a clue.
Would you head over to the
place I'm about to tell you?
今から云う場所に向かってくれないかな
You discovered the enemy's hideout?
敵のアジトがわかったのか
Yup.
そう
Did their soldiers tell you?
兵士が吐いたのか
Nope...
いや
But we were able to get
results from a dried leaf
靴底に付着していた広葉樹の枯葉から特定できた
that was stuck to the bottom
of one of their shoes...
It was indeed a leaf.
葉っぱだよ
The one who betrayed the
organization, Sakaguchi Ango...
組織の裏切者　坂口安吾
His information must be here.
その情報がここにあるのだろう
Dazai's subordinates should
be getting here soon.
間もなく太宰の部下達もここに来る手筈だ
I wanted to check out the
facility before that.
その前に　施設を調べておきたかった
Because I had a hunch...
ある予感があったからだ
Odasaku-san?
織田作さん　来てはいけません
You mustn't come here!
Why did you come here?
何故ここに来たのです
This was the facility the enemy
was using as their hideout!
ここは敵が根城にしていた施設ですよ
I thought you might have needed some help.
お前が扶けを求めてるような気がしてな
僕は扶けなんて求めてない
I didn't need any help!
Really?
そうか
Let me deduce one of the reasons
that you're troubled right now.
お前が困っている理由を一つ推測してみよう
Mimic found out that you were a spy.
ミミックにお前が間諜だとバレた
That's...
それは…
ポートマフィアの誰もがお前はミミックの間諜だと思ってる
Everyone in the Port Mafia believes
you're a spy for Mimic.
But it's the opposite.
だが逆だ
Sakaguchi Ango is a Port Mafia
spy that infiltrated Mimic.
坂口安吾はミミックの中に潜んだポートマフィアの間諜だ
The reason those guys were looking
into your room with a sniper's scope
奴らがお前の部屋を狙撃スコープで覗いていたのは
部屋にあった「灰色の幽霊」を奪われないようにする為だ
was so that the Graugeist, hidden
in your room, wouldn't be stolen.
But why didn't they hurry up and
snipe the boss of the Port Mafia?
だが奴らは何故手っ取り早くポートマフィアの首領を狙撃しなかった
それはお前が首領の居場所はわからないと嘘をついていたからだ
That's because you lied, and said you
didn't know where the boss was.
The reason you did that, as well as
everything you said or didn't say,
何故そんなことをしたのか
お前が何を話して何を黙るかは
凡て首領が決めといたからだ
were all determined by the boss.
織田作さん　逃げてください
Odasaku-san, please run...
僕としたことがしくじりました
I, of all people, messed up...
There are time bombs hidden
throughout this building...
この建物の至る処に時限爆弾が仕掛けられています
They were planning to burn me to death
for being the traitor that I am!
奴らは裏切者である僕をきれいさっぱり焼き殺す心算だ
なんだ　やっぱり扶けを求めてるじゃないか
See?
You were asking for help.
行くぞ　安吾
Let's go, Ango!
How much longer until the bombs go off?
爆発までどれくらいだ
I believe you'd be able to tell
with your powers.
あなたの異能力のほうがわかるのでは
Like my gift is that convenient...
そんな便利な能力があるか
But...
だが　まだ数秒はあるようだ
It looks like we still
have a few seconds left!
Odasaku-san?!
織田作さん
We're going to jump!
飛ぶぞ
Pardon?!
はい？
Are you all right?
大丈夫か
I'm not cut out for all this adventure.
こんな冒険活劇　僕には無理です
But... You saved my life.
でも　助かりました
How much does our boss know?
うちの首領はどこまで知ってるんだ
Nearly everything.
ほぼ凡てです
The only one who knew about me
infiltrating Mimic was the boss.
ミミックに潜入したことを知っているのは首領だけでした
So the reason the boss had me
look for you was for insurance.
首領が俺に安吾探しを命じたのは保険だな
Because he knew that I would look for you,
even if I didn't know the truth.
俺なら　真実を知らなくても　迷わず安吾を助けると踏んだわけだ
早く報告しなくては
I have to report to him immediately.
The head of Mimic is an
extremely dangerous man.
ミミックの長は危険な男です
He plans to crush the Port Mafia.
ポートマフィアを完全に潰す心算だ
What's the head's name?
その長の名は
His name is Gide.
長の名はジイド　強力な異能力者です
He has a very powerful gift.
We mustn't fight him.
奴と戦ってはいけません
Odasaku-san, especially you.
織田作さん　特にあなたは
The gun that was in that lockbox,
the Graugeist, is a sign.
金庫に入っていたあの銃　「灰色の幽霊」は符牒です
There is a special carving
in the cocking piece,
撃鉄に特別な彫り込みがあって
and that proves that you
are a member of Mimic.
それがミミックの一員であることを証明します
ミミックというのは何者なんだ
What the hell is Mimic, anyway?
They are the remnants of
those defeated in the war,
戦場以外では生きられない　旧大戦の敗残兵です
that can only survive on the battlefield.
They are all still haunted by the war...
彼らは今でも戦争に憑りつかれていて
What's that...?
あれ　何です
A ball?
鞠？
Crap...
しまった
It's poison...
毒か
俺の異能力「天衣無縫」は　数秒先の未来を予見できる
My ability, Flawless,
allows me to see a few
seconds into the future.
But in the cases where I've realized
the danger in the future
だが　未来に起こる危機を察知した時　既に罠にはまっている場合は
after already falling for the trap,
回避できない
I can't avoid it...
The person who set up this
trap knew about my powers...
この罠を仕掛けた奴は俺の能力を知り尽くした奴だ
Ango... Run...
安吾　逃げろ
織田作さん
Odasaku-san...
先ほど僕がお話ししたミミックの内情は凡て真実です
Everything that I just told
you about Mimic is the truth.
It is not a lie.
嘘偽りはありません
Thank you for saving me.
助けていただいて　有り難う御座いました
Take care.
お元気で
If it were possible,
もし許されるなら　太宰君と三人でもう一度酒を飲みたかった
I would have loved to go drinking
with you and Dazai-kun again
at the usual place.
いつもの店で
There are those who actually think
異能力者の中には異能力が女性を口説く道具だと思っている莫迦までいる始末です
that powers can
be a tool to seduce women.
But we couldn't use our abilities to
seduce women, even if we wanted to.
我々の異能力は女を口説く道具にしたくっても　できないじゃないか
Even if we tried, they'd think
we're creepy and we'd fuzz up.
寧ろ気味悪がって　口説いてもしゅっぱいする
しゅっぱい？
"Fuzz up"?
Yup. Fuzz up.
あぁ
しゅっぱいさ
Sorry, Dazai...
すまんな　太宰
Looks like I fuzzed up...
どうやら…
Next Time: Episode 15
A Room Where We Can Someday See The Ocean
しゅっぱいだ
我々はミミック
神の恩寵から見放されし死霊の軍団
乃公と戦え　作之助
貴君だけが我らの魂を焼き尽くすことができる
断る
俺は人を殺さない
ならば貴君にも見せてやろう
乃公の頭の中にある地獄を
夢があった
いつかゆっくり机に座って
次回　文豪ストレイドッグス　第十五話
いつか海の見える部屋で